[
    {
        "question": "The word economics comes from ............... word.",
        "options": [
            "Latin",
            "Greek",
            "English"        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "In capitalist economy the means of production are owned by ............... individual",
        "options": [
            "Private",
            "Public",
            "Personal"        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Mixed economy aims at achieving a balance between profit and ..............",
        "options": [
            "Growth",
            "Development",
            "Social welfare"        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The micro-unit of an economy is a ............... ",
        "options": [
            "Village",
            "Family",
            "State"        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "In socialistic economy the means of production are under ..................... control",
        "options": [
            "State",
            "Political",
            "Psychological"        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The macro unit of economics is the ............... .",
        "options": [
            "District",
            "Region",
            "World"        ],
        "answer": 3 
    },
    {
        "question": "In capitalistic economy the main aim is to earn ...............",
        "options": [
            "Profit",
            "Social justice",
            "Social welfare"        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Globalisation means aligning the country's economy with the ............... economy.",
        "options": [
            "Regional",
            "World",
            "State"        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Economics help us to understand how to use time, money, labour and land ...............",
        "options": [
            "Substantially",
            "Effectively",
            "Initially"        ],
        "answer": 2
       },
    {
        "question": "............... mean family management.",
        "options": [
            "Oikonomia",
            "Social-welfare",
            "Profit"        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Economics studies how to satisfy the infinite needs of the people using various ...............",
        "options": [
            "Income",
            "Resources",
            "Taxes"        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The ............... relates to the production, distribution and consumption of goods and services.",
        "options": [
            "Factory",
            "Industry",
            "Enterprise"        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Economics is a science which studies human ............... as a relationship between ends and scarce means.",
        "options": [
            "Aspect",
            "Behaviour",
            "Interests"        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "An economy strives to create a ............... between limited resources and unlimited needs",
        "options": [
            "Trade",
            "Balance",
            "Exchange"        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "An economy tries to ................ the production costs as much as possible.",
        "options": [
            "Minimise",
            "Maximise",
            "Change"        ],
        "answer": 1
    }
]